_
The timing was good.
I just got a job transfer,
Gretchen will start at a new school...
We're gonna start a whole new life.
It's very exciting.
In college,
my dad majored in cheerleading.
That was a joke.
Gretchen's got a great sense of humor.
I'm laughing on the inside.
Soon you'll be laughing
on the outside, too.
Dr. Park.
Moebius Syndrome is a paralysis
of the 6th and 7th pair
of cranial nerves.
The 7th pair controls facial expression.
Luckily, in Gretchen's case,
we haven't found any limitation
to the 6th pair.
I'm a lucky girl.
We'll be taking two slivers
of muscle from your thighs,
along with their nerves
and blood supply,
and transplanting them into your cheeks.
There'll be considerable recovery time
before you'll be able
to smile at will...
maybe three months.
So, what do you say?
Are you up for this?
Can I sleep on it?
See what I have to live with?
Nobody knows when I'm joking.
Sorry, Dr. Andrews.
Yes, I am very up for this.
Okay, great.
So unless there are
any other questions...
Do you want to be a comedian?
People getting your jokes
must be very important to you
if you think it's worth the risk
of dying during elective surgery.
Synced & corrected by kinglouisxx
www.addic7ed.com
I apologize for Dr. Murphy.
He's still learning
that silence is the right choice
when you have nothing useful to offer.
We are required to have an honest
risk/benefit discussion
with our patients.
We are giving
a lovely young girl a smile.
That's a simple equation.
Well, it's more than the smile
or the jokes.
She can't express any emotions at all.
No one can tell if she's happy
or sad or scared... anything.
She's never had much of a social life.
Ever since her mother died,
she's been completely withdrawn.
All I want to do is bring my
baby girl back into the world.
Don't worry, Mr. Milman,
we're gonna take great care
of her, all right?
Lucy has a post-op infection
of unknown origin.
Infusing 900 milligrams of clindamycin.
It's terrible, isn't it?
Yes, it is.
- Have you been changing your dressing?
- Every day.
- Soaking it in clean, warm water?
- Yes.
Taking your antibiotics...
one pill, three times a day?
That's a no.
Lucy, I know I gave you a scrip
for antibiotics,
along with one for pain meds.
Why haven't you been taking
your antibiotics?
Did you have a bad reaction
to them, or...?
I never filled my prescription.
I didn't think it was necessary
until it got really bad,
and then I was too weak to go myself,
and I didn't have anyone
to pick it up for me.
Okay. Mystery solved.
I'm sorry.
I know it was stupid.
Very stupid.
Okay.
Hey, Shaun.
Oh. Hello.
I haven't seen you in ages.
What's... What's new?
I'm buying an apple.
I can see that.
- Here, I-I-I'll get it for you.
- No, thank you.
Thank you, Shaun.
What else is new?
You didn't want to be friends.
Um, yeah, no, I...
We... We... We... We're colleagues.
You know, we're... Whatever we are,
we can still talk... We should talk.
I have a new friend. Kenny.
Here you go.
Thank you, Debbie.
Kenny, huh? That's, uh, that's great.
Do you have a new friend?
No.
- Okay.
- Thank you.
Thank you.
We can talk.
You know, we can talk about sports,
we can talk about weather,
we can talk about...
Debbie?
Why would you want to talk about Debbie?
Debbie was flirting with you.
She was?
Yes.
I noticed her exhibiting
two typical signs.
- Not the trifecta, huh?
- No, no the trifecta,
- and one atypical sign.
- I think she's just trying to be friendly.
She gave you an extra dollar in change.
And the fact that you didn't notice
means you like her, too.
Maybe she's just bad at math.
My dad said
that you're on the spectrum...
That's why you said that
about people getting my jokes.
People always get my jokes.
Then you're very lucky.
That was a joke.
I see what you did there.
Yes.
They call me "Resting Gretch Face."
"Shaun the Moron."
Not very witty...
I'm obviously quite smart.
I drew this to their attention.
I'm on a spectrum, too.
Somewhere between inscrutable,
unapproachable, and...
actively scorned.
I don't want to be more approachable,
and I prefer people
not reading my emotions...
they're mine.
That's what you do with friends.
You really think
this surgery's too risky?
Possible complications include embolism,
hemorrhage, collateral paralysis,
asymmetry, brain damage, and stroke.
It's also expensive
and medically unnecessary.
Okay, look straight ahead.
There's a two-hour wait in
the E.R., and what are we doing?
Treating a woman
because she willfully ignored
doctors' orders.
I know what a "Parasite"
looks like, and it's not Lucy.
So this is a Mom thing with you.
Growing up with a whack mother means
that you can identify any
and all problem personalities.
And that is the sole upside
to my miserable childhood,
- thank you.
- Well, at least you had a mom.
Mine died when I was 6,
and Dad instantly married
a child-hating bitch
with a butt-load of debt.
Morgan, I'm sorry.
I didn't tell you to get sympathy...
just that I know "Parasites," too.
Got you booked
first thing tomorrow morning.
Dad.
What? Too soon?
It's...
You're nervous. I get it.
If you have any more questions,
feel free.
I've changed my mind.
I'm not having the surgery.
Murphy.
Hello.
Gretchen's father is very upset.
It seems you talked her
out of the surgery.
No, I didn't talk her out of it
or talk her anywhere.
I just gave her
the list of potential risks.
Embolism, hemorrhage,
collateral paralysis,
- asymmetry, brain damage, and stroke.
- Stroke?
Yes, there was a case in Brazil in 2004,
and the patient suffer...
It seems that you don't believe
that restoring this girl's smile
is that important.
Smiles are overvalued.
There are studies that support that.
And there are studies that don't.
When we smile, we produce endorphins.
They make us happy.
They make other people happy.
When we see smiles,
our basotemporal lobes are activated,
and we duplicate what we see.
Murphy, smiles are contagious.
You see?
I feel good, you feel good...
Everybody likes smiles.
I don't.
In any case, your smile wasn't sincere
since it didn't demonstrate
the Duchenne Marker...
There was no involvement
of the orbicularis oculi muscles
around the eyes,
which means you didn't
release endorphins.
You know, if you can talk her
out of a surgery she's wanted for years,
I'm pretty sure a conversation
with someone objective
can talk her back into it.
Get Park, come with, and keep quiet.
Okay.
Dr. Kalu.
Remember me?
"Fish girl"?
Uh, hi. Celez.
- Hi.
- Yeah.
Yes, uh, of course I do.
I hope it's okay that I requested you.
I'm glad you did.
How are you doing?
Oh, that's what you're going to tell me.
I've been wearing the, uh, tilapia skins
for five months.
I'm getting really tired
of being followed home
by stray cats.
How's the pain?
Compared to what it was?
Nothing.
Uh, any... any fever,
itchiness, or swelling?
Nope.
Well, it looks very good.
But?
How much longer?
Um, how do you feel about tomorrow?
Seriously?
I never joke about tilapia.
What's the matter?
I-I just wasn't expecting that.
I...
I'm afraid of how I'm going to look.
You're going to look beautiful.
Tomorrow.
I know Dr. Murphy informed you
about the risks of this surgery,
and some risks are significant
and some just aren't.
This is as close to risk-free
surgery as we can get.
It'll give you a smile,
it'll let you laugh...
No.
Dr. Murphy didn't talk me out of it.
He inspired me.
He helped me realize
that this could actually
make me stronger.
I don't want to run from it anymore.
Yeah, she's lying.
She's a smart, sarcastic young woman,
not exactly someone who's prone
to inspirational stories.
Why would she lie
about changing her mind?
Well, when I was a cop,
I had a lot of people change their
minds about testifying in court,
and it always came down
to one of three reasons...
fear, confusion, or they were paid off.
She doesn't seem confused.
And I don't think she's afraid.
So Gretchen was paid off?
I admit the analogy isn't perfect.
It's close enough.
Guess who's back in the E.R.
You're happy,
so I'm guessing
it's a noncompliant patient.
You misjudged Lucy.
She made an honest mistake
forgetting her prescriptions.
You called her, didn't you?
She didn't spontaneously remember,
you had to remind her.
Is that a Mom thing, too?
Gretchen, are you worried
that your dad can't afford this surgery?
The insurance company is paying for it.
Dad...
I know it isn't.
It's elective.
It's medically unnecessary.
No one can put a value on your smile...
not bullies, not an insurance company,
not even Dr. Murphy.
In my opinion,
this surgery's medically necessary.
Gretchen, sweetie...
my first memory of your mother
was of her smiling at me
from across the room.
And because of that smile,
we ended up with you.
And... And my last memory memory of her
is that radiance
lighting up the world one last time.
I mean, we never had much money,
but as long as I had that smile,
it didn't matter.
I love you, Dad.
And that's why
I can't let you
give up everything for this.
Lucy Callard?
I'm here.
Um, Lucille Elizabeth Callard?
Yes, that's me.
A Dr. Browne called me
to pick up my prescriptions?
You're the victim
of identity theft, Lucy.
There's an imposter
using your name and medical ID
to get benefits.
Did you have your purse stolen recently?
Six weeks ago.
And you had your driver's license
and credit cards replaced,
but not your health-insurance card?
Is this why the pharmacy refuses
to fill my prescriptions?
I'm on pain meds
for post-herpetic neuralgia.
It's getting really bad.
Once the imposter filled
her prescription for pain meds,
the pharmacy must have thought
- you were overfilling opiates.
- Oh!
It always flares up when I get upset.
Don't worry, Lucy,
we'll get you your meds.
We... We can't.
We're already treating "Lucy Callard."
Nice game, Tony.
Hi, Jim.
- Marcus, hey. You coming or going?
- Neither.
15-year-old girl
with Moebius Syndrome...
your company denied coverage.
No respiratory issues, deformities,
pain, she doesn't even drool.
She's fully functional.
She can't smile... That's a function.
Marcus, I think it's wonderful
you want to give
this little girl her smile,
but if we pay for everything
wonderful, we'll go bankrupt, huh?
And then who are we helping?
We all know doctors
cheat diagnoses to get coverage.
"Deviated septum"
gets you a free nose job,
"migraine" gets you Botox.
Do you really want me to play that game?
This isn't a game for me.
We're a reputable company
with very high standards.
Very high bonuses that get even higher
with your denial rate.
I was gonna suggest we end this
before we say something we'll regret,
but I believe that just happened.
Gretchen's socially isolated, depressed,
and that's only gonna get worse.
What if she slashes her wrists?
You'd prefer to cover that?
Are you threatening me
with a teenage girl's suicide?
And God forbid
something does happen to her,
'cause I'll make sure
that this conversation's
part of the permanent record.
Dr. Andrews said smiles are contagious,
and I'm testing that hypothesis.
Well, I'm not sure your study
will prove anything.
It might have something to do
with the lack of the Duchenne Marker.
Oh, yes.
But here you go.
That wasn't a smile.
Sure it was.
I want to show you something.
You need to follow me.
Okay.
The impostor has poisoned
the real Lucy's medical record.
We have to go through every medication,
every notation, every test
to determine whose is whose.
Doing that with zero tolerance
for errors
could take six months.
Well, the paperwork
is our problem, not hers.
Not if the confusion results in
a harmful treatment
or incorrect diagnosis.
Well, we have to do something.
This woman is in serious pain.
So we treat her...
just be clever about it.
Shaun.
Shaun, I've already
had two iced coffees...
Debbie. Hello, Debbie.
- Shaun.
- You flirted with Dr. Glassman.
Oh, my God.
'Cause I have a new friend,
and he needs one, too.
- I'm so sorry.
- Okay. Look, Dr. Glassman,
Debbie's facial proportions
are close to optimal, okay...
.38 vertical and .48 horizontal...
- I'm so sorry.
- ...so you should find her attractive.
Thank you?
S-S-Shaun... I-I'm so sorry.
And I think you're both Jewish.
Tribal commonality is highly
conducive to social bonding.
Shalom?
Bullies can't put a value on your smile,
nor can Dr. Murphy,
but it seems the insurance company can.
They've agreed to pay $43,750,
about 85% of the entire cost.
I can cover the rest of that.
I swear.
Oh, sweetie, please,
let me do this for you.
Okay.
"Jane Doe"?
That's the only way
that we can treat you right now.
Go home and get some rest.
The records department will
call you to sort all this out.
A year ago, I was playing tennis.
And then the shingles hit,
and I was laid up for six weeks,
and I've been on pain meds ever since.
I lost my job, my husband
treats me like I'm an old lady,
and my daughter thinks I'm too medicated
to be around the new baby.
Maybe I'll be better off as "Jane Doe."
_
The imposter returns.
Lucy?
Lucy, can you squeeze my fingers?
"Lucy"?
She's in septic shock.
Order a lactate level, blood cultures,
and a broad-spectrum antibiotic.
I'll tell Melendez
we've initiated Sepsis Protocol.
We should report her.
She's a criminal and a flight risk.
And very, very sick.
We should put someone outside her door
and arrest her when she's stable.
We don't report
patients we find with drugs
or non-violent people with guns.
We do report people who steal from us.
What would happen
if people who needed our help
thought they would be arrested?
If they thought they would be
arrested for stealing an ID,
maybe they wouldn't steal an ID.
I don't remember anything
in the Hippocratic Oath
about checking payor sources
before treatment.
Strongly suggesting
there was no health insurance
in 4th century B.C., Greece.
We have a duty to treat,
and we have the right to get paid.
But first things first.
Oh, God, I really do not want to be sued
by either one of these women.
Maintain the pretense.
And as soon as she's stabilized,
we're gonna press charges.
Dr. Park, pull the muscle, please.
We don't want any excess
gathering in the suture line.
Thank you.
Okay, remove retractors.
Ready?
Are you sure you don't want
something for the pain?
No. No, I'm good...
as long as you keep talking to me.
Especially if you share
something, uh, very painful.
Painful?
Mm.
Okay...
like the time
I mistook my biology teacher
for my girlfriend and
picked her up in the hallway?
Yeah... twirled her around three times
before I realized my mistake.
That kind of painful?
You may have to dig
even deeper than that.
How about...
the time I finally found myself
in the perfect situation?
You know, work, friends, future...
something I never really had before.
Maybe that's why I screwed it up.
You're not responding to the antibiotics
like we'd hoped...
Lucy.
You know, don't you?
When the real Lucy Callard showed up,
it kind of gave you away.
Is there anyone we can contact?
Do you have any children?
A son.
But he'd be so ashamed of me.
Where is he?
College...
first one in our family.
I had to choose between premiums
and tuition.
Your son is very lucky
to have such a loving mother.
I just wish you got your antibiotics
when you got your pain meds.
I didn't get either medication.
Are you sure?
Because the real Lucy was having
problems with the pharmacy.
I didn't want to risk
using the card again.
Is she okay?
Maybe it's time to move on...
take the lesson with you,
find new friends.
I went to Denver
for an interview last week.
And?
And... we're done.
Really?
Take a look.
Hey, trust me.
See? Beautiful.
The kid, college...
it's just a convenient sob story.
Why would she lie if she may be dying?
Here's what we don't know
about fake Lucy...
whether her story is true.
Here's what we do know...
She's a liar who just found out
she's busted.
Speaking of lies,
that shingles virus that
the real Lucy had last year?
According to Dr. Spindler
at Santa Clara General,
she had it the year before, too,
and according to Dr. Millhouse
at SF Muni,
the year before that.
She wasn't denied the pain meds
because of our imposter.
She was denied
because she is a garden-variety addict.
Well-played, sir.
Dr. Park says the surgery went well.
It's been too long.
What has?
She should be breathing
on her own by now.
Even after prolonged anesthesia,
it should only take 60 to 90 minutes.
Is she okay?
She should have
protective airway reflexes,
motor activity,
and a return of consciousness.
I need to page Dr. Andrews, STAT.
What's going on?
Something bad.
Gretchen's glucose
is within normal limits
and her electrolytes are also normal.
And we've ruled out hyper
and hypothermia.
It doesn't leave much.
What about hypoxia?
Uh, she maintained normal oxygen,
as well as end tidal CO2
throughout the entire case,
and we've given reversal agents...
which we will repeat.
Do you feel bad?
It's okay.
You told them it was close to risk-free.
They knew there were risks,
and I told them, too.
Get a CT.
Rule out clots, hematoma,
bleeding, and stroke.
WBCs and lactate are rising,
O2 sat and MAP are falling.
The Sepsis Protocol isn't working.
Multiple Organ Dysfunction Syndrome.
Medications?
Another antibiotic,
ah, continue crystalloids,
- increase her vasopressors?
- Low-dose steroids?
Give 'em all at try, and
intubate her and insert a swan.
And, yes, I understand
this is out of our own pocket.
Um, do anything exciting for Purim?
Purim. Uh, no.
Yeah... you know, the usual.
Mm.
Ate a little matzah,
and celebrated our
"Exodus from slavery"...
which I think is Passover and not Purim.
The truth of the matter is,
I'm only half Jewish,
so only half the knowledge.
The truth is I-I'm not Jewish at all.
- Ah.
- Yeah.
Yeah, my first husband was.
So I guess we have our
lack of Jewishness in common.
You know what, Debbie?
I think I-I should get going.
Okay. Well, it was...
it was nice, uh, finally
meeting you, officially.
Same.
Oh, no, look at that!
A 1975 300D,
one of the most perfect Mercedes ever
just got a little less perfect.
I beg to differ.
If you're looking for perfection,
you look no further than the 1967 280SE.
Cabriolet or coupe?
The coupe... an all-time classic.
Well, an owner of a 300SL Gullwing
might argue otherwise.
A Gullwing?
Yeah.
Can I get you another coffee?
Iced, large, black.
- That's it.
- I know.
That's a little bit unsettling, Murphy.
Okay.
Why are you studying
the current of ions during electrolysis?
Uh, it's not the chemical
kind of transference.
It's the doctor-patient kind.
I'm dealing with a personal situation.
I don't think
the Internet is very helpful
for solving personal situations.
True.
But I can't exactly ask Claire
for her advice,
and I barely know Park, and Morgan...
Morgan would be bad.
Very bad.
I'm a person.
Yeah.
No, no... Yeah, of course, Shaun.
I'd, uh, I'd love your advice.
Okay.
Uh, so I think Celez, my burn patient,
has feelings for me, and I...
may have feelings for her, too.
But there's a good chance
her feelings aren't real,
and if they are real,
then they may not be permanent.
Uh, you know, it's kind of
textbook transference...
she's grateful and she's vulnerable.
And all I've ever known in my life
is unrequited love...
...from Claire and from my parents.
And that makes me vulnerable, too.
You should call in sick.
Lea says calling in sick is all you need
to gain superior wisdom and knowledge.
She was right.
The CT showed no abnormalities,
and the reversal agents have
been repeated without effect.
So what else could it be?
Anoxic brain injury,
a complication of anesthesia.
Unfortunately, we believe...
your daughter is brain dead.
What?
All for a smile...
I made her think she wasn't
good enough the way she was.
I should've listened to you.
Yes.
There's just no predicting
how individuals will react
to anesthesia.
Yeah.
Park!
You just walked out on that man.
The last thing
a grieving family member needs
is to see their doctor tap out.
Maybe she's still under anesthesia.
Succinylcholine...
It was one of the anesthetics
Gretchen was administered.
- Yeah.
- Now, what if she has
a Plasma Cholinesterase Deficiency?
It'd mean her body couldn't
break down that specific drug.
Complete deficiency is extremely rare.
I've never personally seen it,
and I don't know anyone who has.
Yeah, but if she does have it,
she's just gonna wake up.
Should I tell the father?
No, not yet.
No way we're letting him grieve twice.
Your labs are not improving.
Your organs are shutting down.
You're running out of time.
I'd like to stop calling you "Lucy."
You're welcome...
Beatrice.
What are you doing?
Corneal reflex.
It's mediated by the nasociliary branch
of the ophthalmic branch.
What does it mean?
It means we were wrong.
She's gonna be just fine.
Thank you, Doctor. Thank you.
Thank y...
Oh.
Thank you, Dr. Murphy.
Honey, you're gonna be okay.
You're gonna be just fine.
I was drawing a bath, and I
leaned over to turn it off,
and I dropped the pill bottle,
and before I could fish it out...
All the pills were ruined.
So you need a refill.
My pain has made me so clumsy.
Lucy, you're a liar
and a cheat and an addict.
We know about
the frequent prescriptions,
the multiple doctors,
and the ever-recurring shingles.
You have a serious medical problem.
Let me help you.
Three months?
Hopefully.
But we might be able to give you
a pretty good idea
of what you're gonna look like.
Those things by your ears
are neuro-stimulators.
When we activate them, instant smile.
Sound good?
Dr. Murphy.
It's your mother's smile.
She seemed like a good template.
There is no Duchenne Marker.
Her smile is not real.
Thank you.
But all the other ones are.
All the other ones are.
I spoke with Jim Ransler,
who made it very clear that
we owe him big time for this.
Don't worry, Marcus, I can handle him.
I'm very impressed.
It was all very presidential of you.
You really went above and beyond.
Yes, I did.
I thought I was saving her life...
instead, I nearly ended it.
Celez, hi.
This is the brilliant Dr. Murphy.
He'll be assuming your care
from here on,
though I don't expect you'll need much.
I understand.
I don't think you do.
You see,
doctors aren't allowed
to date their patients.
What are you doing tomorrow?
Uh, I'm calling in sick.
I think you may still have
some friends here.
I guess there is one upside to all this.
If she hadn't bought
the stolen insurance card,
the real Lucy wouldn't be
in rehab right now.
Surprisingly nice.
I told her what she needed
to hear to get help.
Trust me, I get it...
too soft, people take advantage of you.
But with your badass upbringing,
no one messes with you.
Upsides everywhere.
You have way more street cred than, say,
someone whose mom's
a Johns Hopkins cardiologist,
whose dad's a pathologist,
and whose parents have been
happily married for 37 years.
Coming from privilege... zero respect.
Must be really hard to overcome.
- I'll call a code.
- No.
There's nothing left to save.
Time of death, 8:14 P.M.
I'll notify her son.
Oh, hey.
Um, my homies decided to pop by
and, uh, play some Texas Hold'em,
so I'm gonna have to take a
rain check on that pizza night.
You got a 70inch flat-screen, too.
Uh, no. I borrowed yours.
Makes no sense for us both
to have one, right?
Plus homies got to watch March Madness.
- Okay.
- Oh, um, sorry, amigo.
It's four-player Texas Hold'em.
- I don't like poker anyway.
- Hey, Shaun.
Look, you're a great guy,
um, but you got a few,
like, quirks, you know?
And that...
It doesn't really...
jive with this kind of face time.
You get what I'm saying, right?
I love you, man.
I once drove a 300SL...
Thank you... a 300SL Gullwing.
On the road?
No.
For 200 feet at the Concours d'Elegance.
Oh, in Pebble Beach...
That's just as cool.
The car show... You know it?
Of course, yeah.
This year, they're featuring
a Rollston Coachwork display.
Including the Mercedes SS?
- I don't know.
- Ah!
But we should find out.
Do you want to go?
I couldn't.
Yeah, no, I...
Why?
No reason.
I just... I just... thought
that I should make that my first
response before I accepted.
Can I get you anything else?
No, thank you.
We'll just take the doorstop.
I'm sorry. Um, well...
Well, you can bring the doorstop.
Aaron?
Sorry. Um...
The thing...
The thing... The thing...
The thing that... that...
that t-tells you how much
to pay, the... the doorstop.
Could you call a...
Can you call an ambulance, please?
- Mm-hmm.
- Thank you.
Synced & corrected by kinglouisxx
www.addic7ed.com
www.tvsubtitles.net